Natural Language Processing, even with its current challenges,
即使面临目前的挑战 自然语言处理
holds a lot of promise.
也充满前景
To help us better understand how NLP is being used today,
为了帮助我们更好理解今天如何运用自然语言处理
we have with us Armen Pischdotchian from IBM.
我们邀请了 IBM 公司的 Armen Pischdotchian
Hello. My name is Armen.
你好 我是 Armen
In my current role as an Academic Tech Mentor I lecture and conduct
目前担任学术科技导师 我使用 Watson 认知服务
workshops using Watson Cognitive Services for universities,
为大学 高中
highschools, STEM programs, and the girls who code.
STEM 专业和女程序员进行讲课 组织工作坊
We also run hackathons using IBM Watson Cognitive Services that reside on Bluemix,
我们也使用 IBM Watson 认知服务运行编程马拉松 (hackathon)
our platform as a service.
这项服务位于 Bluemix 服务平台上
Another aspect of the work that we do is often wearing a Solution Architect cap because
我们做的另一项工作是经常装扮成系统架构师
most universities are also working with clients who
因为大学也与客户进行合作 这些客户
use the academic environment as their development arena.
使用学术环境做为开发场地
I especially look forward to such extended engagements where I strive
我非常期待这类拓展式合作 我会
to build a proof of concept for such clients. And you're right, Arpun.
竭力为这样的客户构建概念实证 你说的没错 Arpan
We are seeing an increasing number of projects that use NLP in one way or another.
我们已经了解到 越来越多的项目使用不同方式的自然语言处理
And it is being used today, not in isolation,
如今自然语言处理 并不是单独使用
but embedded as part of intelligent end to end solutions that use a number of
而是嵌入在智能端对端解决方案的一部分 使用大量各种技术
different technologies often augmented with
通常提升认知视野
understanding vision and not just a bag of words.
而不只是纸上谈兵
I see. So, what would you say is the primary role of NLP in such a system?
我明白了 那你认为自然语言处理在这样系统中的主要角色是什么呢？
NLP is characterized as a hard problem in computer science.
自然语言处理在计算机科学中是一大难题
Human language is rarely precise or plainly spoken.
人类语言几乎不准确 无法清晰表达
To understand human language is to understand not only the words
理解人类语言 不仅是要理解词汇
but the concepts and how they are linked together to create meaning.
还要理解概念 以及如何组合在一起形成意思
Despite language being one of the easiest things for humans to learn,
虽然对人类来说语言是很容易学习的
the ambiguity of language is what makes
但是语言的模糊性导致
Natural Language Processing a difficult problem for computers to master.
计算机难以掌握自然语言处理
For example, consider this phrase,
例如思考这个短语
this fountain is not drinking water.
这个喷泉不是饮用水 (this fountain is not drinking water)
A cognitive system that can tokenize, parse,
认知系统可以对词组拆分字段 分析
and annotate the phrase will infer that
并添加注释 推断出
the fountain is currently not engaged in the act of drinking water.
喷泉与喝水行为无关
But we know that it means we should not drink the water from this fountain.
不过我们知道 这是说我们不应该从这个喷泉中喝水
Today's systems go beyond analyzing utterances.
如今的系统不仅可以分析话语
They understand the relationship of the words,
它们理解词语之间的联系
the context surrounding the utterances.
话语前后的语境
For example, why do I need to scan through dozens of airbnb reviews to find
例如我可以更好地用语言描述自己的需求时
a suitable accommodation when I can better describe what I want in my own words?
为什么需要浏览几十个 Airbnb 评论 找到适合的住宿呢？
I am looking for an apartment with views of the river,
我要寻找一个可以看到河流的公寓
facing the Manhattan skyline,
可以俯瞰曼哈顿
but I don't want a noisy and smelly location.
但我不想要嘈杂和脏臭的位置
I expect the cognitive system to uncover
我希望认知系统可以找到
customer reviews that depict exactly the criteria that I am seeking.
顾客的评论 准确描述我要找的标准
And that's where NLP comes in.
因此自然语言处理派上用场
It can help understand the user's intentions and what
它可以帮助理解用户的意图
they like or dislike and process large volumes of
了解他们的喜恶 处理大量文本
text to better infer the context of
来更好地推断我们对话的语境
our conversations and just exactly what we mean by what we say.
和我们所表达的准确含义
Here's an example for you, Arpun.
这是为你准备的例子 Arpan
A wise man is absolutely not the same as a wise guy.
聪明人与聪明的家伙肯定不相同 (A wise man is absolutely not the same as a wise guy)
Consider this, a slim chance is the same as a fat chance.
思考这句话 机会渺茫相当于机会很小 (a slim chance is the same as a fat chance)